A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation photographs FA003
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Finland
  - University of Helsingfors - Neurophysiology
    - Dr. Wrede working in dark room, 1937; 9.5 inches x 7 inches; Black and white
      Caption on image: “Dr. Wrede working in the upper dark room. In this room only the amplifier is shielded. It is seen in its box to the left in photograph. Camera to the right. Opposite camera, in the picture just to left of it, end of microscope of string galbanometer. Not possible in this room to use instrument of faster period" "Institute of Physiology, University of Helsinki, Finland. Dark room equipped with apparatus for research in visual phipiology" "Used in PR 1937 p. 24"
    - Scientists working in dark room, 1938; 9.5 inches x 7 inches; Black and white
      Rockefeller Foundation Photo # 21414e
    - Electrically shielded dark room, 1938; 9.5 inches x 7 inches; Black and white
      Rockefeller Foundation Photo # 21414b
      Caption on image " Electronically shielded dark room in cellar, with cathode ray oscillographs for simultaneous recording from retina and nerve. Assistant Dr. Therman at the camera in the adjoining room. No electrical lines or contacts in the room from the mains to to exclude disturbances" "Ragnar Granit, Finland, Neurophysiology"
  - Helsinki College of Nursing
    building, discussion, meeting,
  - Agriculture
    crops, agriculture, fields, club work, people, children, group photos,
  - Biochemical Institute of the Foundation for Chemical Research
    seedlings, apparatus, equipment
  - Helsinge Health Center
    building, interiors, people, child, speech,
  - School of Social Sciences - Displaced Persons Study
    houses, homes, people, children, cleared forrest,
  - University of Helsinki
    horse, cow, testing, lamb, examination, animals, specimen, mouse, reindeer, inoculation,
  - Uusimaa Field Training Area 1949-1953
  - University of Helsinki - Medical School 1957-1958
    microphotograph, calf sclera,
  - University of Turku - Biochemistry 1957-1958, 1962
    chart, dna?,
  - University of Turku - Medical School, Equipment 1948, 1951-1955
    buildings, map,
  - University of Helsinki - Virus Research, Reprints 1961
    charts, graphs,
- Poland
  - General
    John D. Rockfeller Sr. plaque,
  - Pulawy Agricultural Institute
    buildings exteriors, columns, arches,
  - University of Cracow - Library (B. Franklin Exhibit)
    buildings, interiors, exhibit, letter, drawing,
  - Medical Sciences
    buildings, group portrait,
  - Nursing
    buildings, exteriors, faculty, group portraits, nurses,
  - Natural Sciences
    buildings, exteriors, interiors, hallway, corridor, laboratory, equipment,
  - Nencki Institute of Experimental Biology - Neurophysiology
    laboratory, animal testing, surgery, operation, equipment,
  - Hospitals
  - Public Health
    buildings, group portrait, medical examination, interiors, office, waiting room, children,
  - Health Demonstration at Skierniewice, Poland 1924
    buildings, construction, hut
  - Sanitary Institutions of the Sejmik of Warsaw
    buildings, exteriors, hospital interiors, operating room, wards, patients, group portraits,
  - Public Health Education
    buildings, group portrait, audience,
  - University of Cracow - Library
    old damaged book pages, restoration,
  - Jan Casimir University
    building exteriors, interiors, rooms, group portrait,
  - Polish Academy of Sciences - Vari-Typer 1957-1960
    document pages,
  - Science Program - Warsaw School of Agriculture 1957-1958
  - Gdansk Medical Academy - Biological Chemistry 1960-1962
    document page,
  - [CLOSED] Warsaw Medical Academy - Biernacki, Andrzej 1957-1959
    document, letter,
  - Warsaw Post Graduate Medical Institute - Hartwig, Walenty 1958-1960
    documents, letters,
  - Habuz, Barbara 1960-1962
  - Hunter, Rachela 1959-1962
  - Bilski, Eugeniusz 1961, 1963
  - Nencki Institute of Experimental Biology - Neurophysiology, Reports 1960-1963
    document, book, pages,
  - Skierniewice Research Inst. of Pomology-Pieniazek, Szczepan Aleksander, Janina
- Spain
  - General
    Palace,
  - Institute of Physics and Chemistry
  - Nutrition
    children, group photo, medical examination, equipment,
  - Medical Sciences
    drawing, aerial view,
  - Hospitals
  - Hookworm
    mine shaft elevator, cable transportation, people, laboratory, building exterior, iron ore,
  - Malaria
    buildings, exteriors, laboratory, tanks, stream, dipping, fieldwork, spraying, water, lake, well, street,
  - Public Health
  - Public Health Education
  - Institute of Economic Research (Barcelona)
    interiors, library, hallway, corridor, reading room,
  - University of Madrid - Physiology 1958, 1961, 1963-1965
- Sweden
  - General
    portrait
  - Boys and Girls Club Work
  - Fysikalisk - Kemiska Institutionen, Upsala
    apparatus, laboratory equipment,
  - Karolinska Institute
  - School of Public Health, Gothenburg
    architectual, drawings, floorplans, maps,
  - Karolinska Institute - Biochemistry
    larvae, microscopes, laboratory, equipment, machinery, group portraits, graphs,
    - Scientists at microscopes in laboratory for specialized microscopical procedures, 1949; 8 inches x 10 inches; Black and white
      Label on image: "Karolinska Institutet - Inst. for Cell Research - NS 1949" Caption on image: "Laboratory for specialized microscopical procedures. Might also be christened 'Diligence' if anyone believes in it."
      Rockefeller Foundation Photo # 22471b
    - Men at machines in workshop, 1949; 8 inches x 10 inches; Black and white
      Rockefeller Foundation Photo # 22471a
      Label on image: "Karolinska Institutet - Inst. for Cell Research - NS 1949" Caption on image: "Workshop"
    - Universal microspectograph, 1949; 8 inches x 10 inches; Black and white
      Rockefeller Foundation Photo # 22471c
      Label on image: "Karolinska Institutet - Inst. for Cell Research - NS 1949" Caption on image: "Universal microspectograph Prof. Carperra"
    - Scientists in spectrographic laboratory, 1949; 8 inches x 10 inches; Black and white
      Rockefeller Foundation Photo # 22471d
      Label on image: "Karolinska Institutet - Inst. for Cell Research - NS 1949" Caption on image: "Spectrographic laboratories"
    - Scientist using x-ray microspectroscope, 1949; 8 inches x 10 inches; Black and white
      Rockefeller Foundation Photo # 22471e
      Label on image: "Karolinska Institutet - Inst. for Cell Research - NS 1949" Caption on image: "X-ray micropsectrography Ass. prof. Engshoen"
    - Scientist using switchboard, 1949; 8 inches x 10 inches; Black and white
      Rockefeller Foundation Photo # 22471f
      Label on image: "Karolinska Institutet - Inst. for Cell Research - NS 1949" Caption on image: "Part of main distributuion switchboard"
    - Scientists using universal microspectograph, 1949; 8 inches x 10 inches; Black and white
      Rockefeller Foundation Photo# 22471g
      Label on image: "Karolinska Institutet - Inst. for Cell Research - NS 1949" Caption on image: "Universal Microspectrograph, Left Prof. Carpassor, Right Research Assistant Aquilonies" "L-7019 37-12" "used RF ___ 1949 p 205" "37/8"
    - Scientists working in spectrographic laboratory, 1949; 8 inches x 10 inches; Black and white
      Rockefeller Foundation Photo # 22471h
      Label on image: "Karolinska Institutet - Inst. for Cell Research - NS 1949" Caption on image: "Spectrographic laboratories, Right: Ass prof Thorell" "787A Univ Helsingfers Neurophysiology 1938" "used PR 1949 P57" "Russo: one photographic copy, please" "A research project at the new spectrographic laboratories of the Istitute for Cell Research, Karolinska Institute, Stockholm" Stamped on image: "Blues & Hold" "Please return to the Rockefeller Foundation Office of Publications"
      Existence and Location of Copies note
      A duplicate copy of this photograph exists in the same folder.
    - Professor Hugo Theorell examining apparatus, 1955; 8 inches x 10 inches; Black and white
      Rockefeller Foundation Photo # 23143e
      Caption on image: "used in 1955 Annual Report." "Professor Hugo Theorell, recipient of the Nobel prize in medicine in 1955 examining apparatus for measuring magnetic susceptibility at the Medical Nobel Institute in Stockholm. The Foundation's 1955 grant of $45,000 to Professor Theorell's researches in enzyme chemistry continues support which began in 1933."
    - Scientists using apparatus, 1955; 8 inches by 10 inches; Black and white
      Rockefeller Foundation Photo # 23143d
      Caption on image: "From left to right - Hugo Thorell, Ake Akeson, Karl Gustav Paul, Anders Ehrenberg" "Apparatus for measuring magnetic susceptibility"
    - Scientists examining apparatus, 1955; 8 inches x 10 inches; Black and white
      Rockefeller Foundation Photo # 23143c
      Caption on image: "From left to right: Ake Akeson, Anders Ehrenberg, Stephen Kuby, Hugo Theorell and Karl Gustav Paul" "An apparatus for simultaneous determination of the light absorption and oxidation reduction potentials"
    - Staff in preparation laboratory, 1955; 8 inches x 10 inches; Black and white
      Rockefeller Foundation Photo # 23143b
      Caption in image: " Part of the staff in the big preparation laboratory "
    - Scientists next to apparatus, 1955; 8 inches x 10 inches; Black and white
      Rockefeller Foundation Photo # 23143a
      Caption on image: " From left to right: Stephen Kuby, Anders Ehrenberg, Hugo Theorell, Karl Gustav Paul" "Same apparatus as on picture I"
    - Director's study, 1941; 6 inches x 4.5 inches; Black and white
      Rockefeller Foundation Photo# 21785c
      Caption on image: "Director's study" "removed from picture drawer"
    - Assistant's room, 1941; 6.5 inches x 4.5 inches; Black and white
      Rockefeller Foundation Photo # 21785d
      Caption on image: "Assistant's room: inside cage chamber for work on mammals" "removed from picture drawer"
    - Assistant's laboratory, 1941; 4.5 inches x 6.5 inches; Black and white
      Rockefeller Foundation Photo # 21785e
      Caption on image: "Assistant's laboratory outside the cage of [illegible] cathode ray oscillograph [illegible] and [illegible] for [illegible] cathode ray and last stage of amplification" "taken from pictures drawer"
    - Part of the Director's laboratory, 1941; 7 inches x 4.5 inches; Black and white
      Rockefeller Foundation Photo # 21758a
      Caption on image: "Part of Director's Laboratory: loud speaker, double-ray cathode ray oscillograph, camera" "removed from picture drawer"
    - Director's Laboratory, 1941; 7 inches x 4.5 inches; Black and white
      Rockefeller Foundation Photo # 21785b
      Caption on image: " Director's Laboratory: [illegible], Wright colorimeter, binocular preparation microscope, switch-board for high capacity [illegible] cells, amplifiers etc. [illegible] him of a metal net." "removed from picture drawer"
    - Electrotechnicians building apparatus, 1949; 4.5 inches x 3 inches; Black and white
      Rockefeller Foundation Photo # 22501f
      Caption on image: "The technical dept. is led by engineer Mr. H. Wagner who with 2 specially trained electro technicians is engaged in an extensive program of building electrical apparatus for the lab. Wagner (at right) & the 2 electro technicians, Mr. Persson (left) and Mr. Karlsson (center), are shown." "used - RF Annual 1949, page 154" "Ragnar Granit"
    - Report depicting people working in the Nobel Institute for Neurophysiology in Stockholm, 1948 - 1949
      Rockefeller Foundation Photo # 22501a-e
  - Swedish State Institute for Race Biology and Human Genetics
    building, laboratory, interior, van, vehicle, automobile, equipment,
  - University of Lund - Endocrinology, Kahlson
  - University of Upsala - Physical Chemistry - 1
    buildings, construction, interiors, laboratory, equipment, lighting, lamps, stools, rooms,
  - University of Upsala - Physical Chemistry - 2
    interiors, laboratory, equipment, library, machinery, classroom,
  - Agriculture
    group portraits, camps, tents, club exhibitions, pig, hog, land, plot, inspection,
  - Karolinska Institutet - Biochemistry, Cell Research - Thorell
    laboratory, equipment, machinery, charts, diagrams, cells,
    - Scientists working with apparatus, 1960; 8 inches x 10 inches; Black and white
      Rockefeller Foundation Photo # 24235b
      Caption on image: "Fig. 1" "Professor Hugo Theorell, Mr. Ake Akeson, Nobel Medical Institute, Caroline Institute, Stockholm, Sweden"
    - Scientists constructing apparatus, 1960; 8 inches x 10 inches; Black and white
      Rockefeller Foundation Photo # 24235a
      Caption on image: "Constructing an apparatus for the automatic analysis of amino acids" "Fig. 2" "Professor Hugo Theorell, Mr. Ake Akeson, Nobel Medical Institute, Caroline Institute (crossed out) Karolinska Institute, Stockholm, Sweden" "Used AR/PR, 1960"
    - Scientists adjusting optical ultramicrospectrograph, 1955; 9.5 inches x 7 inches; Black and white
      Rockefeller Foundation Photo # 22994c
      Caption on image: "optical ultramicrospetrograph, Dr. Gunnar Svensson, Miss Ulla Sundwall"
    - Scientists seated at optical ultramicrospectrograph, 1955; 9.5 inches x 7 inches; Black and white
      Rockefeller Foundation Photo # 22994b
    - Optical ultramicrospectrograph, 1955; 9.5 inches x 7 inches; Black and white
      Rockefeller Foundation Photo # 22994a
      Caption on image: "optical ultramicrospecrtograph"
    - Scientists examing optical ultramicrospectrograph, 1955; 9.5 inches x 7 inches; Black and white
      Rockefeller Foundation Photo # 22994d
      Caption on image: "used in RF AR 1954" "optical ultramicrospetrograph, Dr. Gunnar Svensson, Miss Ulla Sundwall"
  - Royal Agricultural College of Sweden - Plant Sciences
    diagram, chart, laboratory equipment,
  - Swedish Academy of Sciences - Cyclotron
    buildings, exteriors, laboratory, equipment, machinery, cyclotron, magnet, ion chambers, group portrait,
  - Swedish Seed Association
    laboratory, greenhouse, plants, spraying,
  - University of Gothenburg - Cytochemistry
    laboratory, equipment, machinery, microscope,
  - University of Lund - Genetics
    view, building, greenhouse, laboratory, equipment, plants, machinery, research, testing,
  - University of Stockholm - General
    laboratory, equipment, machinery, building, exterior, interiors,
  - University of Uppsala - Biochemistry, Physical Chemistry
    laboratory, equipment, machinery, construction, apparatus, buildings,
  - University of Gothenburg - Latin American Studies
  - University of Gothenburg - Latin American Studies, Wassen
    profile, portrait,
  - University of Uppsala - American Studies
    building, library, interior, reading room,
  - University of Stockholm - Social Sciences Institute
    building, library, reading room, offices, conference, meeting,
  - Karolinska Institutet - Biochemistry - Theorell, Hugo 1949-1952
    architectual drawings,
  - Karolinska Institutet - Cell Division
    charts, diagrams, equipment, machinery,
  - Medical School, Gothenburg - Spectroscopy 1950-1956
    diagrams, equipment, machinery,
  - Swedish Seed Association 1954, 1956-1959
  - University of Gothenburg - Cytochemistry 1956-1960
    cells, microphotograph,
  - University of Stockholm - Entomology (Box 166, Folder 3206)
    Portrait.
- Sweden - Natural Sciences and Agriculture
  - University of Stockholm - Entomology (Box 166, Folder 3206)
- Switzerland
  - University of Zurich - Neuropsychiatry
    cat, feline testing, equipment, laboratory,
  - Geneva - Zoology
    buildings, gardens,
  - Jungfraujoch - Astronomy
    buildings, mountains, alps,
  - Technical High School, Zurich - Biochemistry, Plant Physiology
    laboratory, equipment, machinery, cell,
  - University of Berne - Botany
    laboratory, interior, equipment, greenhouse
  - University of Geneva - Chemistry
    professors, laboratory, men, discussion, enzymes, crystals,
  - Hospitals
    building, drawings of views
  - Technical High School, Zurich - Giedion
    ceiling carvings, art, clay,
  - Geneva Graduate Institute of International Studies
    conference, meeting, seminar, men, building, library, interior,
  - University of Basel - Economics
    men, woman, meeting, group photo,
  - University Institute of Higher International Studies
  - Swiss Institute of Public Hygiene, Geneva 1947-1948
    floorplans,
  - University of Berne - X-ray Crystallography 1950-1952, 1955-1958
  - Technical High School, Zurich - Giedion, Siegfried 1951-1955
    sculpture, artwork,
  - University of Basel - Economics 1952
    book pages,
- Near East Region
  - Emergency Relief
  - Food and Agricultural Organization Trainees 1963
    group portrait, men,
  - Wheat Improvement
    wheat, field, stalks, inspection,
  - Arab Thought Conference - Bhamdbun, Lebanon
    conference, meeting, discussion, men,
- Turkey
  - Constantinople College
  - Collin - Black Sea Trip Diary, September 1926
    views, building,
  - Population Council - Technical Assistance
    lecture hall, speaker, people, audience,
  - Medical Sciences
    buildings, landscape, group portrait,
  - University of Ankara - Pediatrics
    surgery, operation, buildings, model, fire, construction, medical laboratory, equipment,
  - American Hospital of Istanbul - Deniz
    views, hospital rooms, patients, nurses, eating, classroom, dining room, medical examinations, surgery, recreation, athletics,
  - Nursing
  - University of Ankara
    nurses, patients, nursing, rehabilitation, children,
  - Public Health
    fountain, water trough, letter, building, students, medical officers,
  - Public Health Education
    views, buildings, exteriors,
  - University of Ankara - Turkish and Islamic Art
    photography equipment, library, office
  - Eyuboglu, Bedri Rahmi
    art, mosaic, flooring,
  - University of Ankara - Ural, Zeki Faik 1952-1953, 1956-1958
  - University of Ankara - Ornek, Sevim Bike 1955-1957
    rotten teeth, mouth
  - Kent Player's Theatre 1962-1964
    scenes, actors, acting,
- Crete
  - McIntosh [or] MacIntosh
    microscope, views, buildings, exteriors, ruins, streets, group portraits, portrait, village, people, pottery, windmills,
  - Regional Development 1949-1951
    village, streets, views, people, windmills, group portraits, portraits, buildings, market, donkeys, transportation, well, food, goats,
  - Regional Development - Supp. Mat. RegDev-1, Part 1- Petrakis, Sdrin & Naxakis
    maps, buildings, artwork, ruins,
  - Regional Development-Supp. Mat. RegDev-1 Part 2 - Allbaugh, Leland G.
    maps, view, group photo,
  - Regional Development-Supp. Mat. RegDev-1 Part 3 - Mickey, Jean Learned
    water sources, pumps, views, firetruck, people, map, charts, graphs, buildings, vilaages, markets,
  - Regional Development-Supp. Mat. RegDev-1 Part 4 - Woods, Ralph H.
    group photos, children, dancing, buildings, Frontispiece,
  - Regional Development-Supp. Mat. RegDev-1 Part 5 - Allbaugh, Leland G.
    maps, charts, graphs, olive plant,
  - Regional Development-Supp. Mat. RegDev-1 Part 7 (pg.1-94) - McIntosh, William A.
    buildings, portraits, views, villages, ruins, pottery, people, microscope, streets, roads,
  - Regional Development-Supp. Mat. RegDev-1 Part 7 (pg 95-201) McIntosh, William A.
    water sources, buildings, exteriors, people, views,
  - Regional Development-Supp. Mat. RegDev-1 Part 7 (pg 202-291) McIntosh, William A
    woman, midwife, building exterior, people,
  - Regional Development-Supp. Mat. RegDev-1 Part 7 (pg 292-376) McIntosh, William A
  - Regional Development-Supp. Mat. RegDev-1 Part 9 - Allbaugh, Leland G.
    charts, graphs, maps, buildings, blankets, ruins, views, windmills, pottery, markets, mule packs, transportation,
  - Regional Development-Supp. Mat. RegDev-1 Part 10 - Allbaugh, Leland G.
    buildings, views, people, streets, motorcade, parade, portraits,
- Cyprus
  - Malaria
  - Health Services
    drainage,
- Egypt
  - General
    dam, water, donkey, natives, people, buildings,
  - Africa and Asia Minor Region Report - JMW
    interviews, people, natives, medical examination, treatment, inoculation, latrine, construction, boring, digging, well, lake, village,
  - Bilharziasis Conference
    people, meeting, speaker, conference, group portrait,
  - Cholera
    view, buildings, DDT spraying, Cairo
  - European Office
  - Schistosomiasis
    charts, snails, collecting, canals, dry beds,
  - Soper Trip - Typhus Study
    people, donkeys, transporation, village, tents, examinations, buildings, water, views, portraits, group photos, fields, palm trees, canal, pyramids, river, boats,
  - Virus Diseases
    laboratory, equipment, animal testing, diagrams, inoculation, building, exterior,
  - World Health Organization
    satellite photos, aerial views, specimens, organisms, parasites,
  - Hookworm
    hookworm, disease, patients, tent, treatment, latrine, construction, laboratory, equipment,
  - Scott Manuscript
    streets, housing, houses, river, buildings,
  - Malaria
    water sources, sampling, examinations, latrine construction, buildings, views, streets, people, group portraits, cells,
  - Public Health
    models, sanitation exhibit, latrine,
  - Sanitary Engineering
    refuse, garbage, dump, equipment, sludge, landfill, fly traps,
- Saudi Arabia
  - Malaria
- Israel
  - General
  - Hebrew University
  - Tel-Hashomer Government Hospital - Blood Groups
    diagrams,
  - Tel-Hashomer Government Hospital - Blood Groups, Reprints 1959-1963
    book pages, red cell membrane,
  - Hebrew University - Agricultural History 1958-1962
    views, fields, canals, flood, plants, agriculture, trees, vegetation, water, channel,
  - Hebrew University Agricultural History 1959-1960
    agriculture, fields, views, water channel, flood gate, plowing, camels, wheat, harvesting,
  - Israel Fruit Growers Association - Sive, Arye 1961-1962
    equipment, apparatus,
  - National Physical Laboratory - Solar Energy 1961
    solar power, panels, equipment, apparatus,
  - National Physical Laboratory - Solar Energy 1961-1964
    solar power, plant, panels,
  - Koller
    lettuce tree,
  - Malaria 1923-1927
    houses, housing, homes, water supply, springs, dry beds, road, car, vehicle, transporation, bridge, irrigation, ditch, bathing pool, latrine, exhibit,
  - "Field Studies in Palestine" - Carley, Paul S., 1922
    drainage ditch, malaria case, disease, map, views, people, dynamite explosions, holes, spray canister,
  - Public Health
    group portrait, health exhibit, pharmacy, plumbing,
  - American School of Oriental Research, Jerusalem
  - Hebrew University [circa 1962]
    turkey inoculation, bleeding, testing,
  - Israel Foundation Trustees - Virus Studies 1955-1956
    charts, information,
  - Israel Foundation Trustees - Virus Studies 1957
    Israel map, graph,
  - Israel Foundation Trustees - Virus Studies 1958
    graph, chart, diagram, maps,
- Syria (Lebanon)
  - American University of Beirut 1921-1938
    street, buildings, views, statue, exteriors, interiors, assembly hall, people, group portraits,
  - American University of Beirut - Medical School
    buildings, view,
  - American University of Beirut - Medical School - Hirsh, Victor - Report
    nurses, children, patients,
  - American University of Beirut - Neurophysiology 1921-1963
    equipment, cage,
  - American University of Beirut - Nursing School 1929-1935
    group portraits, nurses,
  - Fellowships - Scholarships
  - Asfuriych Hospital
    views, buildings, exteriors, portraits, people, doctors, nurses, patients, car, vehicle, transportation, ruins, donkey,
  - Public Health Demonstrations
    exercising, weighing, children,
  - American University of Beirut - Arabic Studies
    meeting, conference, seminar, speaking, studying, teaching,
  - Yale - Archeology
    ancient road, ruins,